this brings us to Branch prediction
requirements what do we need in order to
successfully predict whether a branch is
taken or not and where is it going if
it's taken Branch fiction needs to work
using only the knowledge of where we
fetch the current instruction from and
what we needed to guess is the PC of the
next instruction to fetch so a branch
pictor must correctly guess is this a
branch if not then it's certainly not
taken if it is a branch is it taken and
if it is a taken Branch what is the
target PC where is this Branch going
these two decisions really can be boiled
down to one which is is this a taken
Branch it doesn't matter if we have a
non- branch instruction or a non-t taken
Branch instruction in both cases we just
fetch the instruction that follows the
branch in memory so the only thing we
really need to decide is whether this is
a taken Branch or something else